Lewis Watson

Senior Software Engineer

KY2, Kirkclady, Fife GB

http://lewiswatson.co.uk | mrlewiswatson@gmail.com

Software Engineer with 9+ years experience spanning Cloud Web Applications down to embedded C applications. Currently a Senior Application Developer at CGI's Open Digital Services Centre where we specialise in developing customer solutions using open source technologies.

SKILLS

Integration	Web Services	Cloud
jboss fuse esb activemq messaging apache camel drools bpms spring framework	rest soap	azure rackspace openshift containers (docker)
Data	Build Chains	Web Development
postgresql mongodb mariadb/mysql microsoft sql server	apache maven msbuild apache ant jenkins gnu make	html5 css/sass javascript extjs bootstrap

Backend Languages

java | c/c++ | javascript | python

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer at ODSC - CGI UK

May 2014 - Current

http://www.cgi-group.co.uk/

One of the first hires to CGI's newly opened Open Digital Services Centre in Glasgow, which specialises in developing solutions around Open Source and Open Standards. I have been fortunate to be involved in shaping some of the processes and culture of the office

- Currently senior developer on a project developing an Enterprise Service Bus to connect an Automated Traffic Management System to roadside devices. I'm gaining experience developing using technologies such as Red Hat JBoss Fuse Integration Services, Red Hat Openshift Cloud, Kubernetes, Apache Camel and Apache ActiveMQ.
- Previously lead two projects for two separate public sector customers. One to deliver a data analysis system using ElasticSearch + MongoDB, and the other to modernize and automate a clients web service infrastructure. Both solutions were deployed using docker containers.
- Senior developer on a remote agile scrum team developing Java components for a large public sector project. During this time I gained experience with Apache CXF, JBoss Fuse ESB, and JBoss Portal.
- Produced a number technology demonstrations to aid in attracting business to the centre. This involved technologies such as docker, database virtalization, MongoDB, JBoss Fuse Enterprise Service Bus, Open Data Geospatial systems, Hadoop, and Lumify big data analysis + visualisation platform.

Software Engineer at Thales UK

June 2007 - May 2014

https://www.thalesgroup.com

Joined the Thales Graduate Development program straight from university and worked with them for 7 years. During this time I gained full stack development experience spanning web technologies (front-end and back-end) down to embedded application development.

- Developed a web based inventory tracking system with a HTML5 user interface (ExtJS, jQuery, Bootstrap) served by a PHP/ASP backend connected to a MySQL database. My role also involved design, server configuration, replication, app deployment, and setting up a Continuous Integration environment for my team.
- Technical lead for a project developing an Engineering Resource Management system that automatically matched engineers to roles within the company. A key feature was the use of a business rules management system (BRMS) that enabled site administrators to change the applications business logic on the fly, allowing the system to rapidly adapt to changing priorities.
- Technical consultant for a team developing Windows C++ applications that used Nvidia CUDA to perform calculations on GPU's. I advised on best practice, converted the Visual Studio code to compile in GCC and install via the RPM Package Manager in Linux. I also designed and implemented an automated process for deploying the

system into production devices via PXE network boot and a custom flavour of Fedora Linux.

- Developed a big data system designed to enable a major project to exploit large data sets more efficiently. I took on the roles of Software Architect, Developer, and Sysadmin in order to design, implement, and deploy a solution. The system incorporated C++ worker processes controlled via a HTML5 web app.
- Upgraded network interfaces on hard real-time embedded C application

EDUCATION

Bsc Hons Computer Science at Heriot-Watt University 2003 - 2007

LANGUAGES

English

Native speaker

INTERESTS

Technology

Side Projects

Skills acquired: containers | cloud | Skills acquired: my workshop | open source / open standards | my home office | my shed novel uses of web technologies (e.g. nodejs and electron)